Samsara is a documentary film directed by Ron Fricke.
Filmed over nearly five years in twenty-five countries on five continents, and shot on seventy-millimetre film, Samsara
transports us to the varied worlds of sacred grounds, disaster zones, industrial complexes, and natural wonders.
Dancer: Valinese Tari Legong Dancers, Indonesia,
played by Ni Made Megahadi Pratiwi.
Dancer: Valinese Tari Legong Dancers, Indonesia, played by Puti Sri Candra Dewi.
Dancer: Valinese Tari Legong Dancers, Indonesia, played by Putu Dinda Pratika.
Tattoo Daddy: USA, played by Marcos Luna.
Professor and Robot Clone: Japan, played by Hiroshi Ishiguro.
Man At Desk: France, played by Olivier De Sagazan.
Samsara is a 2011 American non-narrative documentary film of international imagery directed by Ron Fricke and produced
by Mark Magidson, who also collaborated on Baraka (1992), a film of a similar vein, and Chronos (1985).
Completed over a period of five years in 25 countries around the world,
it was shot in 70 mm format and output to digital format.
The film premiered at the 2011 Toronto International Film
Festival and received a limited release in August 2012.
The film explores themes of eating, around the world, balance, skyline, sunset.
The tone is thought_provoking.